Previously on the show.
上集說到
The little beans wanted to help others,
小精靈熱心想幫助別人
but they always end up making a mess.
可總是幫倒忙
With guidance from the goats,
在小羊的點撥下
they finally realized their problem
他們終於認識到自己的問題所在
and made amends for their mistakes.
成功彌補了之前的錯誤
So what will happen next?
那麼接下來，又會發生什麼呢？
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: Creating Rainbow."
《奇幻天空島之》
Tibbie, what do you think of the new Magic Train?
美羊羊，覺得這新的嘻哈號怎麼樣？
It's amazing. I didn't expect the magic train to have a morphing function.
太神奇了 沒想到嘻哈號還有變身功能
And my happy skill is so special. It's so much fun.
而且我的嘻哈技能這麼特別 好有趣啊
Looks like each of us has a different skill when operating the Magic Train.
看來我們每個人操控嘻哈號 都有不同的技能
Leader...
領隊
Leader, you're finally back.
領隊你們終於回來了
Weslie, you promised to take us out for a picnic. Let's get going.
喜羊羊他說好帶我們去野炊的 趕快出發吧
Have you packed everything that's needed?
野炊的東西你們都收拾好了嗎？
Fine, I'll help you pack up.
好吧，我幫你們一起收拾吧
Thank you, Leader.
謝謝領隊
They didn't close the door.
居然沒關門，太好了
Great, now's the time.
就趁現在
I almost forgot to close the door.
差點忘記關門
I've finished packing.
我收拾好了
I've got more stuff than you.
我的比你多
I've got the most.
我的才是最多的
Leader, the job of creating the rainbow is on you.
製造彩虹就靠妳了，領隊
Yes, you guys go have fun.
你們好好玩吧
Tibbie, will you be all right alone?
美羊羊，妳一個人沒問題嗎？
Don't worry. We've taught her how to do it.
放心吧，我們已經教過領隊了
And it's all written in the book.
而且，都寫在冊子裡了
Does she have to read the whole book?
要看完這麼一大本嗎？
No, that's just the catalog. The books are here.
不，那只是目錄，冊子在這裡
You have a parcel. Is anyone home?
送快遞，有人在嗎？
Hi, is Tibbie here? These are for her.
你好，請問美羊羊在嗎？ 這些都是她的快遞
Tibbie, what did you buy? It's so heavy.
美羊羊，妳買了什麼呀？好重啊
These are tools and ingredients for making bread.
這都是做麵包的工具和材料
I'm making delicious bread tonight.
今晚要做美味的麵包吃唷
Great.
太好了
I'm so smart. I got in so easily.
我真是機智，這麼輕易就混進來了
Let me catch Paddi first.
先捉住懶羊羊吧
Paddi, let's get going.
懶羊羊，我們準備出發吧
Leader, remember to lock the door.
領隊，大門記得鎖好門鎖啊
Oh. The cabinet is rusty. Can you help me take it to the recycling point?
對了，儲物櫃生鏽了 可以順便幫我搬到回收點嗎？
-Sure.
-好的
Sounds like Tibbie will be alone.
聽起來好像只剩下美羊羊的樣子
What a good opportunity. Oh no, what's going on?
千載難逢的好機會啊，什麼事啊？
-Come on...
-加油…
Why isn't it moving anymore?
怎麼不動了？
Push.
再加把勁
The cabinet's rolling downhill!
櫃子掉下去了
It's so hot.
好燙，好燙啊
Everyone, steer clear!
大家快躲開
The cabinet's rolling downhill.
櫃子掉下來啦
I'm sorry.
對不起
Since everyone's all right, let's go.
既然沒事，我們就出發吧
Let's go!
出發…
Wait, was this lock here?
等等，這鎖剛才有的嗎？
Never mind. I'll open it.
算了，拆
This lock is no joke.
這鎖套路可真深啊
But I'll open it.
可是難不倒我
How many more traps are there?
到底還有多少陷阱
What a waste of my efforts! The back door wasn't even locked.
浪費我這麼多功夫，你們卻不鎖後門
This is so mean!
太過分了
Inject energy before the launch.
發射前注入能量
After that...
完成後就…
Looks like it has stopped raining in some areas.
看來有地方降雨結束了
I must launch the rainbow now.
得趕緊發射彩虹過去
I remember that the color pens must be loaded first.
我記得是先裝入顏色筆
First, it's red... then orange, yellow, green, indigo, blue, and violet.
先是紅…接著是 橙、黃、綠、青、藍、紫
Next, I have to inject energy.
接著導入能源
The injection is done.
導入完成
Humidity, 54 degrees. Wind speed, 4.5 meters per second.
濕度為54度，風速4.5米每秒
Temperature, 36 degrees.
溫度36度
And angle, 40 degrees. Start charging now.
角度40，開始充能
It's fully charged.
充能完成
Launch the rainbow!
發射彩虹
What's the fuss?
什麼事大驚小怪的？
What... What's going on?
發…發生什麼事了？
When youngsters create a rainbow for the first time...
年輕人嘛，第一次製造彩虹…
there's bound to be some mistakes.
肯定會有一點錯誤的
Exactly...
對啊…
Did I do something wrong?
難道是什麼地方出問題了？
I got the temperature and wind speed mixed up.
溫度和風速輸反了
Let me do it again.
再來一次
Humidity, 54 degrees.
濕度54度
Temperature, 36 degrees. Wind speed, 4.5 meters per second.
溫度36度，風速4.5米每秒
Start charging now.
開始充能
Ready for launch!
準備發射
It should be all right this time.
這次我想應該沒問題了吧？
Oh, I forgot to adjust the angle.
忘記調角度了
The angle is 40 degrees. What's wrong?
角度是40度，怎麼了？
Why is it so hard to adjust this?
怎麼會這麼難調啊？
Oh no, it's tilted. What should I do? I can't adjust it anymore.
歪…歪掉了…怎麼辦？調不動了
Right, I can use the Magic Train to align the crystal.
對了，我可以用嘻哈號調正大水晶
I'm so tired after searching through the rooms. Where is Tibbie?
找了這麼多房間，好累啊 美羊羊在哪裡呢？
Freeze, hands up!
別動，雙手抱頭
This room is so weird. What's this?
這房間真奇怪，這是…
That's strange. What is this? Let's try doing this.
奇怪，什麼東西？再試試這樣吧
-Whoever blinks first, loses. -Okay...
-誰先眨眼誰就輸 -好…
The shape of the rainbow is getting weird.
彩虹的形狀越來越奇怪
Tibbie is creating a rainbow for the first time,
美羊羊第一次製造彩虹
so it's normal to have some hiccups.
有一點點的問題很正常
You call this normal?
這也算正常？
Yes, it's normal.
正常…
And it's normal for the rainbow to make faces at us?
彩虹跟我們做鬼臉也正常嗎？
Time's running out. I have to align the crystal quickly.
時間不多了 我要快點把水晶柱調正才行
Wolffy? Why...
灰太狼
why are you here?
你…你怎麼會在這？
Little goat, I've been searching for you. You've finally come to me.
小羊，找了妳這麼久 終於自己送上門來了
She's sitting inside the Magic Train! I have to lure her out.
竟然坐在嘻哈號裡面 我得把她引出嘻哈號
What are you trying to do?
妳想幹什麼？
Trying to catch you.
抓住你啊
It was always the wolf catching the goats in previous episodes. Okay?
以往的劇集都是狼抓羊好嗎？
Anyway, I can't let you make trouble here.
總之不能讓你在這裡搗亂
Again?
還來？
Oops, you missed it. If you have guts, don't hide in the Magic Train.
沒抓到，有本事別躲在嘻哈號裡面啊
It's too cramped here. I might hit the machine.
這裡空間太小了，很容易打到儀器的
Then come down and catch me.
那妳就快下來抓我啊
What a joke! Get out of here right away.
開玩笑，你快點離開這裡
I'm staying. What can you do?
我就是不走，妳能怎麼辦呢？
Stop it, Wolffy! Or else I'll throw you out.
灰太狼不許亂再來 不然就把你扔出去
What? I'm so scared.
什麼？我好怕呀
You won't be able to catch me if you're hiding inside the Magic Train.
妳躲在嘻哈號裡面就永遠抓不到我
Stop it!
你快住手
I got you!
抓到了
Let me go!
快放開我
The claws are so big. How can you catch me?
妳的爪子那麼大怎麼可能抓到我？
Oh no, the claws are too big. What should I do now?
糟了，爪子太大了，現在怎麼辦啊？
No, I must be strong.
不行，我要堅強
I've got an idea.
我想到辦法了
Tibbie, are you tired? Come down and get some rest here.
美羊羊，是不是累了 下來休息一下吧
What?
什麼？
Your tricks don't work on me at all.
妳的招數對我一點作用都沒有
This is my skill.
這是我的技能
You'll keep dancing as long as I play this.
只要我不停地彈奏，你就會一直跳舞
My waist... Tibbie...
腰…美羊羊
Keep on dancing. Don't stop.
跳吧…不要停下啊
Stop... Stop it.
停…停下
I... can't... take this anymore.
我…要…要不行了
The crystal column is finally aligned.
水晶柱調正了
It's about time. I must be quick.
時間差不多了，要抓緊
It's finally over. I'm too tired to move.
終於停下來了，累到不能動了
I will be back!
我一定會回來的
I finally got it right this time.
這次終於發射成功了
We're back.
我們回來了
Welcome home.
歡迎回來
We saw it on our way home. The last rainbow you created was pretty.
我們回來的時候看到了 妳最後造的那條彩虹好漂亮啊
Tibbie, although the first few were a little weird,
美羊羊，雖然前面幾次有點奇怪
you created a proper rainbow in the end.
但最後還是造出了彩虹
That's right. The last rainbow was very pretty.
是啊…最後那道彩虹可美了
Thank you.
謝謝你們
Okay, I'm hungry.
好了，我已經餓了
Let's have some bread now.
我們快點去吃麵包吧
But you ate the most during the excursion. How could you be hungry?
今天野炊你吃的最多，還餓
I'm sorry. I haven't had time to make the bread yet.
不好意思，那個麵包還沒來得及做呢
It's fine. You've worked hard today. We'll make the bread.
沒關係，妳今天已經很辛苦了 麵包就讓我們來幫忙吧
You have us...
還有我們呢...
-And me too.
還有我們
You guys... let's do it together.
大家…那我們就一起做吧
Okay.
好
TO BE CONTINUED 2766 DAYS FROM SETTING SAIL
（未完待續 距離啟程還剩2766天）